
1.Given a number N and N strings of length atmost M, 
  print the longest common prefix.

  Input Size : 1<=N, M<=100000
  Example:
	  INPUT
	   2	
	   Vishal	
	   Vidharba

	  OUTPUT
	   Vi   



2.Given a number N, obtain the smallest number after deleting K digits.

  Input Size : 1<=N<=1000000000000000000
  Example:
	  INPUT
	   213 1
	  OUTPUT
	   13   



3.Given 2 strings X,Y convert X to Y as cheaply as possible. 
  Let the cost of insertion, deletion and updation be 1. Print the minimum cost.

  Input Size : 1<= N<=1000
  Example:
	  INPUT
	   BALL BALOON
	  OUTPUT
	   3  
 

4.Do problem 3 with cost of insertion, deletion as the position of the inserted 
  alphabet in A-Z and substitution as the difference in their positions in A-Z.

  Input Size : 1<=N<=1000
  Example:
	  INPUT
	   arc bug
	  OUTPUT
	   8   


5.Given three numbers N,A,B. Find if it is possible to partition N into 2 
  equal groups containing A and B only.

  Input Size : 1<=N,A,B<=1000000000000000000 
  Example:
	  INPUT
	   20 2 3
	  OUTPUT
	   YES
  Explanation: (2,2,3,3),(2,2,3,3)   



6.Given a number N and an array of N elements, find the number of triplets
  ai < aj < ak(i < j < k) in the array.

  Input Size : 3<=N<=100000
  Example:
	  INPUT
	   5
	   1 3 2 4 5 4
	  OUTPUT
	   4    


7.Given a number N which is the number of people in the tournament, 
  If the tournament starts with number of players N not equal to a power of 2, 
  some players need to be given byes, which transfers players directly to the
  next round because they have no opponent assigned to them. 
  Find the minimum number of byes that has to be given.

  Input Size : 3<=N<=100000
  Example:
          INPUT
	   5
	  OUTPUT
	   1   


8.Given 2 numbers N,Q and an array of N integers, followed by Q queries each 
  consisting of L,R. Find the GCD of numbers in [L,R].

  Input Size : 1<=N<=100000
  Example:
	  INPUT
	   5 2
	   1 2 3 4 5
	   1 2
	   4 5
	  OUTPUT
	   1
	   1    



9.There is a line of 2N counters with no spaces between adjacent counters. 
  The counters alternate between black and white: BWBW ... B W. 
  The objective is to rearrange the counters so that all the white counters are 
  before all the black ones with no gaps between the counters: W W ... WBB ... B. 
  The counters are to be moved in pairs, On each move, a pair of adjacent counters 
  can be moved, without changing their order, into a vacant location
  (either before everything or after everything). 
  What is the minimum number of moves required to solve this problem?
  
  Input Size : 3<=N<=1000
  Example:
	  INPUT
	   3
	  OUTPUT
	   3    



10.Once detective saikat was solving a murder case. While going to the crime scene
   he took the stairs and saw that a number is written on every stair. He found it 
   suspicious and decides to remember all the numbers that he has seen till now. 
   While remembering the numbers he found that he can find some pattern in those 
   numbers. So he decides that for each number on the stairs he will note down the 
   sum of all the numbers previously seen on the stairs which are smaller than the present
   number. Calculate the sum of all the numbers written on his notes diary.
   
   Input Size : 1<=N<=100000
   Example:
    	INPUT  
	  3
	  1 2 3
	OUTPUT
	  4(0+1+1+2)    



11.A kindergarten teacher has to arrange 2n children in n pairs for daily walks. Design an 
   algorithm for this task so that for 2n − 1 days no pair would be the same and print the
   total number of distinct pairs.
   
   Input Size : |2n|<=1000000000000000000
   Example:
	   INPUT
	    4
 	   OUTPUT
	    6    



12.Given 2 numbers N and Q followed by N numbers. Now Q inputs of 2 numbers U and V are given. 
   U indicates the starting index and V indicates the ending index. So for each U,V find the sum 
   of all values of the array from the index U to V (1 based indexing).
   HINT : USE SEGMENT TREE

   Input Size : N<=100000
   Example:
   	   INPUT
	    5 3
	    1 1 1 1 1
	    1 3
	    2 4
	    3 4
	   OUTPUT
	    3
	    3
	    2 



13.Given 2 numbers N and Q followed by N numbers. Now Q inputs of 2 numbers U and V are given. 
   U indicates the starting index and V indicates the ending index. So for each U,V find the minimum 
   of all values of the array from the index U to V (1 based indexing).
   HINT : USE SEGMENT TREE

   Input Size : N<=100000
   Example:
	   INPUT
 	    5 3
	    1 1 1 1 1
	    1 3
	    2 4
	    3 4
	   OUTPUT
	    1
	    1
	    1 



14.Given 2 numbers N and Q followed by N numbers. Now Q inputs of 2 Numbers U and V are given.
   U indicates the starting index and V indicates the ending index. So for each U,V find the XOR of 
   all values of the array from the index U to V (1 based indexing).
   HINT : USE SEGMENT TREE
    
   Input Size : N<=100000
   Example:
	   INPUT
   	    5 3
    	    1 2 1 4 1
	    1 3
	    2 4
	    3 4
	   OUTPUT
	    2
	    7
	    5 



15.You are given an array 'a' of size N. Your task is to print the array one element in a line in the 
   decreasing order of number of ones in its binary representation. In case of two numbers having same
   number of ones, the bigger number in its decimal representation comes first.
 
  Input Size : N<=10000
  Example:
	  INPUT
	   5
    	   31 14 15 7 2
	  OUTPUT
	   31
	   15
	   14
	   7
	   2 



16.There are N children standing in a line. Each child is assigned a rating value. You are 
   giving candies to thesechildren subjected to the following requirements:
	1. Each child must have at least one candy.
	2. Children with a higher rating get more candies than their neighbors.
   What is the minimum candies you must give?

   Input Size : N<=100000 
   Example:
   	   INPUT
	    5
 	    1 2 4 1 2
	   OUTPUT
	    9 



17.Given 2 numbers N and K followed by N numbers find if there exists a pair of numbers such that
   it adds upto K.
   
   Input Size : N<=100000 
   Example:
     	   INPUT
   	     5 4
	     1 2 2 4
	   OUTPUT
 	     yes 



18.Given a binary matrix of size N,X,M consisting only 0s and 1s, find the maximum size square 
   submatrix with all 1s.

   Input Size : N<=1000, M<=1000
   Example: 
	   Consider the below matrix.  
   	   INPUT
	     6 5
	     0 1 1 0 1
	     1 1 0 1 0
	     0 1 1 1 0
	     1 1 1 1 0
	     1 1 1 1 1
 	     0 0 0 0 0
	   OUTPUT
	     1 1 1
	     1 1 1
	     1 1 1
   NOTE
	The maximum square sub-matrix with all ’1′ bits is from (2,1) to (4,3) 




19.There's an array A consisting of N non-zero integers A1..N. A subarray of A is called alternating 
   if any two adjacent elements in it have different signs (i.e. one of them should be negative and 
   the other should be positive). For each x from 1 to N, compute the length of the longest alternating
   subarray that starts at x - that is, a subarray Ax..y for the maximum possible y ≥ x. The length of
   such a subarray is y-x+1.
   
   Input Size : N<=100000   
   Example:
	   INPUT
 	    4
	    1 -5 1 -5
	   OUTPUT
	    4 3 2 1 




20.Given a list of N coins, their values (V1, V2, … , VN), and the total sum S. Find the minimum 
   number of coins the sum of which is S (we can use as many coins of one type as we want), or report
   that it’s not possible to select coins in such a way that they sum up to S.

   Example: Given coins with values 1, 3, and 5. And the sum S is 11.
   Output: 3, 2 coins of 3 and 1 coin of 5
   Input Size : N<=10000 
   Example:
      	   INPUT
	    3 11
  	    1 3 5
	   OUTPUT
	    3 




21.Given a number N and an array of N numbers, find if it is possible to divide the array into 2 
   arrays with equal average.

   Input Size : 2<=N<=100000
   Example:
	   INPUT
	    5
	    4 2 3 4 2
	   OUTPUT
	    yes




22.Given a number N followed by an array of N numbers, find the maximum sum which can be obtained by 
   picking the elements of the array based on the following rule:
	'If you pick the current element u cannot pick its neighbors'.

   Input Size : 1<=N<=100000
   Example:
	   INPUT
	     5
	     1 2 3 4 5
	   OUTPUT
	     9 




23.Given a string S, find if it denotes a circular motion(same initial and final positions).
   The instructions are:
	1)G:Move 1 Unit
	2)L:Turn Left
	3)R:Turn Right

   Input Size : |S| <=10000000
   Example:
	   INPUT
	    GLGLGLG
	   OUTPUT
 	    no 




24.Given K - which is the number of bits, print all the possible combinations of numbers formed by 
   printing all numbers with one bit set, followed by two bits set, ... upto the point when all k-bits 
   are set. They must be sorted according to the number of bits set, if two numbers have the same 
   number of bits set then they should be placed as per their value.
   
   Input Size : 1<=K<=1000
   Example:
	  INPUT
	   3
	  OUTPUT
	   000
	   001
	   010
	   100
	   101
	   110
	   011
	   111 



25.Given a number N and an array of N integers, find the length of the Longest Increasing Subarray.
   
   Input Size : 1<=N<=100000
   Example:
	   INPUT
    	    5
	    1 2 2 1 3
	   OUTPUT
	    2 



26.Given a number N and an array of N integers, find the length of the Longest Increasing Subsequence.

   Input Size : 1<=N<=1000
   Example:
   	INPUT
   	 5
    	 1 2 2 1 3
   	OUTPUT
         3 



27.Given two numbers N,W and two arrays each containing N integers(1 Weight array,1 Value array), 
   print the maximum value that can be obtained by picking a list of elements with total weight<=W.
   
   Input Size : 1<=N, W<=1000
   Example:
    	   INPUT
	    5 5
  	    1 2 3 4 5
	    1 1 1 1 1
	   OUTPUT
	    2 


28.There are N people in a queue. For each person we know time T needed to serve him. A person will be
   disappointed if the time he waits is more than the time needed to serve him. The time a person 
   waits is the total time when all the people who stand in the queue in front of him are served.If we
   swap some people in the queue, then we can decrease the number of people who are disappointed,
   print the maximum number of not disappointed people that can be obtained after swapping optimally.

   Input Size : 1<=N<=100000 
   Example:
    	INPUT 
   	 5
	 15 2 1 5 3
	OUTPUT
	 4 



29.Given a number N, print the number of ways of choosing another number 'x' such that'x+sum of digits
   of x=N' and print each 'x' in a new line.
   
   Input Size : 1<=N<=1000000000
   Example:
	  INPUT
	   21
	  OUTPUT
	   1
	   15 



30.Given a integer N, Your task is to determine if it is possible in this case to remove some of the
   digits (possibly not remove any digit at all) so that the result contains at least one digit, forms
   a non-negative integer, doesn't have leading zeroes and is divisible by 8. After the removing, it 
   is forbidden to rearrange the digits. Check If a solution exists.

   Input Size : 1<=N<=10^100
   Example:
	  INPUT
	   3454
	  OUTPUT
	   yes 




31.Given a number N(number nodes of a graph) and a number M(number of edges). For the next M lines 
   2 numbers U and V are given(2 nodes which are connected). Find the path which has the maximum sum 
   of nodes and print the maximum sum.

   Input Size : N<=10000, M<=10000
   Example:
   	INPUT
	 4 3
	 1 2
	 1 3
	 3 4
	OUTPUT
	 8 



32.Given a 2D matrix of integers, sort it such that:
       - every row is sorted in ascending order from left to right
       - every column is sorted in ascending order from top to down
       - all items in the same row are unique
   You may assume the input matrix is always valid, meaning that such a sort is always possible.
   
   Input Size : N<=500, M<=500
   Example:
   	INPUT
	 2 3
	 1 3 5
	 3 2 4
	OUTPUT
	 1 3 4
	 2 3 5 



33.Given a string S, print the longest substring P such that P > S lexicographically. You may assume 
   that such substring exists.
   Input Size : |S|<=10000
   Example:
   	INPUT
   	 string
   	OUTPUT
	 tring 



34.Chan’s girlfriend's birthday is near, so he wants to surprise her by making a special cake for her.
   Chan knows that his girlfriend likes cherries on the cake, so he puts cherries on the top of the 
   cake, but he was not satisfied. Therefore, he decided to replace some of the cherries to make a 
   beautiful pattern. However, Chan has a lot of other work to do so he decided to ask for your help.
   The cherries are of two colors red and green. Now Chan wants the cherries to be placed in such a way
   that each cherry of one color must be adjacent to only cherries of the other color, two cherries are
   adjacent if they share a side. Now Chan has asked for your help in making that pattern on the cake.
   You can replace any cherry of given color with the other color. But there is a cost for each 
   replacement: if you replace a red cherry with a green one, the cost is 5 units and if you replace a
   green cherry with a red one, the cost is 3 units. Help your friend Chan by making the cake special 
   with minimum cost.
  
   Input Size : N<=1000, M<=1000
   Example:
   	INPUT
	 2 3
	 RRG
	 GGR
	OUTPUT
	 8 



35.You are given a string s consisting of lowercase Latin letters. Character c is called k-dominant 
   iff each substring of s with length at least k contains this character c. You have to find minimum 
   k such that there exists at least one k-dominant character.

   Input Size : |S|<=10000
   	INPUT 
	 abacaba
	OUTPUT
	 2 



36.Shapur has to find weaknesses in the roman army to defeat them. So he gives the army a weakness 
   number. In Shapur's opinion the weakness of an army is equal to the number of triplets i, j, k such 
   that i < j < k and ai > aj > ak where ax is the power of man standing at position x. The Roman army
   has one special trait — powers of all the people in it are distinct. Help Shapur find out how weak 
   the romans are.
   
   Input Size : N<=100000 
   Example:
	INPUT
	 3
	 3 2 1 
	OUTPUT
	 1	 



37.You are given an array a. Some element of this array ai is a local minimum iff it is strictly less
   than both of its neighbours (that is, ai < ai - 1 and ai < ai + 1). Also the element can be called
   local maximum iff it is strictly greater than its neighbours (that is, ai > ai - 1 and ai > ai + 1).
   Since a1 and an have only one neighbour each, they are neither local minima nor local maxima.
   An element is called a local extremum iff it is either local maximum or local minimum. Your task
   is to calculate the number of local extrema in the given array.

   Input Size : N<=1000 
   Example:
	INPUT
	 3
	 1 2 3
	OUTPUT
	 2 



38.There are n students in an institution. For each student you know the number of times he/she has 
   participated in the ACM ICPC world programming championship. According to the ACM ICPCrules, each
   person can participate in the world championship at most 5 times. The head of the institution is 
   recently gathering teams to participate in the world championship. Each team must consist of exactly
   three people, at that, any person cannot be a member of two ormore teams. What maximum number of 
   teams can the head make if he wants each team to participate in the world championship with the 
   same members at least k times?
   
   Input Size : N<=10000
   Example:
	INPUT
	 5 2
	 0 4 5 1 0
      	OUTPUT
	 1	 




39.A tree is a connected acyclic graph. A bipartite graph is a graph, whose vertices can be 
   partitionedinto 2 sets in such a way, that for each edge (U, V) that belongs to the graph, U and V 
   belong todifferent sets. You can find more formal definitions of a tree and a bipartite graph in 
   the notessection below. Consider a tree consisting of n nodes and add edges to it in such a way, 
   that the graph is stillbipartite. Besides, after adding these edges the graph should be simple 
   (should’nt contain loops ormultiple edges). What is the maximum number of edges they can add? 
   A loop is an edge, which connects a node with itself. Graph doesn't contain multiple edges when 
   foreach pair of nodes there is no more than one edge between them. A cycle and a loop aren't the 
   same.

   Input Size : N<=100000, U,V<=N
   Example:
	Input
	 3
	 1 2
	 2 3
	Output
	 0 




40.Given a string S, check whether the given string is an anagram of the string “dhoni”. Anagram of a 
   given string is a permutation of the set of characters present in the string. For example for the 
   string “baba” aabb and baab are anagrams while aaab and bacd are not.
   
   Input Size : |S|<=100000 
   Example:
	INPUT
	 inohd
	OUTPUT
	 yes 



41.Given 2 numbers N,M corresponding to the number of 0 and 1 respectively, print anarrangement of
   cards which satisfies the following conditions:
	1)There wouldn't be a pair of any side-adjacent cards with zeroes in a row.
	2)There wouldn't be a group of three consecutive cards containing numbers one.
   Print '-1' if it is impossible.

   Input Size : 1<=N<=100000
   Example:
   	INPUT
	 1 2
	OUTPUT
	 101 



42.Given 2 numbers N,K followed by an array of N integers perform the following operation:
	1)Split the array into exactly k non-empty subsegments.
	2)Compute the minimum integer on each subsegment.
	3)Take the maximum integer over the k obtained minimums.
   What is the maximum possible integer you can get if u split optimally?

   Input Size : 1<=K<=N<=100000
   Example:
	INPUT
	 5 2
	 1 2 3 4 5
	OUTPUT
	 5 



43.Given a number N followed by an array of N integers with each element in [1,N]. Change (replace)
   minimum number of elements in the array in such a way that the array becomes a permutation 
   (i.e. each of the integer from 1 to n was encountered in his array exactly once). If there are
   multiple ways to do it print the lexicographically minimal permutation among them.

   Input Size : 2<=N<=100000
   Example:
	INPUT
	 4
	 3 2 2 3
	OUTPUT
	 2
	 1 2 4 3



44.Given 4 numbers N,P,Q,R followed by N integers, find the maximum value of P*ai+Q*aj+R*ak(i<=j<=k).
   Input Size : 1<=N,P,Q,R<=100000
   Example:
	INPUT
   	 5 1 2 3
	 1 2 3 4 5
	OUTPUT
	 30 



45.Let quasi-palindromic number be such number that adding some leading zeros (possible none) to it 
   produces a palindromic string. String t is called a palindrome, if it reads the same from left to 
   right and from right to left. For example, numbers 131 and 2010200 are quasi-palindromic, they can 
   be transformed to strings '131' and '002010200', respectively, which are palindromes. You are given
   some integer number x. Check if it's a quasi-palindromic number.
   
   Input Size : 1<=N<=1000000000
   Example:
	INPUT
	 131
	OUTPUT
	 yes 



46.You may have heard of the pie rule before. It states that if two people wish to fairly share a 
   slice of pie, one person should cut the slice in half, and the other person should choose who gets
   which slice. A and B have many slices of pie, and rather than cutting the slices in half, each
   individual slice will be eaten by just one person. The way A and B decide who eats each slice is as
   follows. First, the order in which the pies are to be handed out is decided. There is a special 
   token called the 'decider' token, initially held by B. Until all the pie is handed out, whoever has
   the decider token will give the next slice of pie to one of the participants, and the decider token
   to the other participant. They continue until no slices of pie are left. All of the slices are of 
   excellent quality, so each participant obviously wants to maximize the total amount of pie they get
   to eat. Assuming both players make their decisions optimally, how much pie will each participant 
   receive?

   Input Size : 1<=N<=50
   Example:
	INPUT
	 3
	 141 592 653
	OUTPUT
	 653 733




47.For a given positive integer N denote its K-rounding as the minimum positive integer x, such that x
   ends with k or more zeros in base 10 and is divisible by n. For example, 4-rounding of 375 is 
   375*80 = 30000. 30000 is the minimum integer such that it ends with 4 or more zeros and is divisible
   by 375. Write a program that will perform the k-rounding of N.

   Input Size : 1<=N<=1000000000, K<=8 
   Example:
   	INPUT
   	 375 4
   	OUTPUT
	 30000



48.Two soldiers are playing a game. At the beginning first of them chooses a positive integer n and 
   gives it to the second soldier. Then the second one tries to make maximum possible number of rounds.
   Each round consists of choosing a positive integer x > 1, such that n is divisible by x and 
   replacing n with n / x. When n becomes equal to 1 and there is no more possible valid moves the 
   game is over and the score of the second soldier is equal to the number of rounds he performed. 
   To make the game more interesting, first soldier chooses n of form a! / b! for some positive integer
   a and b (a ≥ b). Here by k! we denote the factorial of k that is defined as a product of all 
   positive integers not large than k.
   What is the maximum possible score of the second soldier?
   The input consists of several test cases.

   Input Size : 1<=T,A,B<=100000 
   Example:
	INPUT
	 2
	 3 1
	 6 3
	OUTPUT
	 2
	 5	 



49.String a is the divisor of string b if and only if there exists a positive integer x such that if 
   we write out string a consecutively x times, we get string b. For example, string 'abab' has two 
   divisors — 'ab' and 'abab'. Given 2 strings of length N,M find the number of common divisors for
   them.

   Input Size : 1<=M, N<=1000000000
   Example:
	INPUT
	 abcdabcd
	 abcdabcdabcdabcd
	OUTPUT
	 2 



50.Given 2 integers N,M(where N is the number of vertices and M is the number of edges) followed by
   'M' lines containing 2 vertices U,V and weight W. Find the shortest path from 1-N.If there is no 
    path print '-1'.
    
    Input Size : 1<=N, M<=100000
    Example:
	INPUT
	 5 6
	 1 2 2
	 2 5 5
	 2 3 4
	 1 4 1
	 4 3 3
	 3 5 1
	OUTPUT
	 5 






51.There's an array A consisting of N non-zero integers A1..N. A subarray of A is called alternating 
   if any two adjacent elements in it have different signs (i.e. one of them should be negative and
   the other should be positive). For each x from 1 to N, compute the length of the longest alternating 
   subarray that starts at x - that is, a subarray Ax..y for the maximum possible y ≥ x. The length of
   such a subarray is y-x+1.
   Example:
	INPUT
	 4
	 1 -5 1 -5
	OUTPUT
	 4 3 2 1 





52.Check whether the given 4 points form a square or not.
   
   Example:
	INPUT
	 10 10
	 10 20
	 20 20
	 20 10
	OUTPUT
	 yes 




53.Given a sentence S, check whether it is a pangram.
   Input Size : |S|<=10000
   Example:
   	INPUT
     	 A quick brown fox jumps over the lazy dog
   	OUTPUT
     	 yes




54.Waking up in the morning, Apollo decided to bake cookies. To bake one cookie, he needs n
   ingredients, and for each ingredient he knows the value ai — how many grams of this ingredient one 
   needs to bake a cookie. To prepare one cookie Apollo needs to use all n ingredients. Apollo has 
   bigram of the i-th ingredient. Also she has k grams of a magic powder. Each gram of magic powder can 
   be turned to exactly 1 gram of any of the n ingredients and can be used for baking cookies. Your
   task is to determine the maximum number of cookies, which Apollo is able to bake using the 
   ingredients that he has and the magic powder.
   
   Input Size : N<=100000, k<=1000000000
   Example:
	INPUT
	 3 1
	 2 1 4
	 11 3 16
	OUTPUT
	 4 



55.A thief made his way to a shop. As usual he has his lucky knapsack with him. The knapsack can 
   contain k objects. There are n kinds of products in the shop and an infinite number of products of 
   each kind. The cost of one product of kind i is ai. The thief is greedy, so he will take exactly k 
   products (it's possible for some kinds to take several products of that kind). Find all the possible
   total costs of products the thief can nick into his knapsack.

   Input size : |S|<=10000
   Example:
	INPUT
	 3 2
	 1 2 3
	OUTPUT
	 2 3 4 5 6  




56.Recently Kohli bought a very interesting book. He knows that it will take t seconds to read the 
   book. Kohli wants to finish reading as fast as he can.But he has some work to do in each of n next
   days. The number of seconds that Kohli has to spend working during i-th day is ai. If some free 
   time remains, he can spend it on reading. Help Kohli to determine the minimum number of day when
   He finishes reading. It is guaranteed that the answer doesn't exceed n. Remember that there are 
   86400 seconds in a day.

   Input Size : N<=100T<=1000000 
   example
	INPUT
	 2 2
	 86400 86398
	OUTPUT
	 2 




57.Design an algorithm to accept 2 strings A and B from the user, and check whether any part of 
   string A (comprising of minimum of 2 consecutive characters) is a sub-string of string B.

   Input Size : A<=1000, B<=1000
   Example:
	INPUT
	 abcxyz hagsaabc
	OUTPUT
	 yes 




58.Dhoni plays his favorite game 'Peace Lightning'. Now he is flying a bomber on a very specific map. 
   Formally, map is a checkered field of size 1 × n, the cells of which are numbered from 1 to n, in 
   each cell there can be one or several tanks. Dhoni doesn't know the number of tanks and their 
   positions, because he flies very high, but he can drop a bomb in any cell. All tanks in this cell
   will be damaged. If a tank takes damage for the first time, it instantly moves to one of the 
   neighboring cells (a tank in the cell n can only move to the cell n - 1, a tank in the cell 1 can 
   only move to the cell 2). If a tank takes damage for the second time, it's counted as destroyed and 
   never moves again. The tanks move only when they are damaged for the first time, they do not move by
   themselves. Help Dhoni to destroy all tanks using as few bombs as possible.
   
   Input Size : N<=1000000 
   Example:
	INPUT
	 2
	OUTPUT
	 3
	 2 1 2 




59.Kedar has ordinary pan scales and several weights of an equal mass. Kedar has already put some 
   weights on the scales, while other weights are untouched. Kedar is now wondering whether it is 
   possible to put all the remaining weights on the scales so that the scales were in equilibrium. 
   The scales is in equilibrium if the total sum of weights on the left pan is equal to the total sum
   of weights on the right pan. The first line has a non-empty sequence of characters describing the 
   scales. In this sequence, an uppercase English letter indicates a weight, and the symbol '|' 
   indicates the delimiter (the character occurs in the sequence exactly once). All weights that are 
   recorded in the sequence before the delimiter are initially on the left pan of the scale. All 
   weights that are recorded in the sequence after the delimiter are initially on the right pan of the
   scale. The second line contains a non-empty sequence containing uppercase English letters. Each 
   letter indicates a weight which is not used yet. It is guaranteed that all the English letters in 
   the input data are different. It is guaranteed that the input does not contain any extra characters.
 
   Example:
	INPUT
	 AC|T
	 L
	OUTPUT
	 AC|TL 




60.Bob has a strange counter. At the first second, t = 1, it displays the number 3. At each subsequent
   second, the number displayed by the counter decrements by 1. The counter counts down in cycles. 
   In the second after the counter counts down to 1, the number becomes 2x the initial number for that
   countdown cycle and then continues counting down from the new initial number in a new cycle. The 
   diagram shows the counter values for each time t  in the first three cycles.

   Input Size : t<=100000
   Example:
	INPUT
	 4
	OUTPUT
	 6




61.Given 2 strings output the encoded string based on the given example.
   Example:
	INPUT
	 core
	 kata
	OUTPUT
	 nplf 



62.Find the length of remaining string from the given string after removing the longest palindrome 
   from it.

   Input Size : |s|<=1000
   Example:
	INPUT
	 abbac
	OUTPUT
	 1



63.Given a string, find the length of the longest substring without repeating characters.
  
  Input Size : |S|<=1000
  Example:
	INPUT
	 abcabcccdd
	OUTPUT
	 3 



64.You are given an array a of size n, and q queries to it. There are queries of two types:
	1) li ri — perform a cyclic shift of the segment [li, ri] to the right. That is, for every x
           such that li ≤ x < ri new value of ax + 1 becomes equal to old value of ax, and new value of
	   ali becomes equal to old value of ari.
	2) li ri — reverse the segment [li, ri].There are m important indices in an array b1, b2,...,bm
	   For each i such that 1 ≤ i ≤ m you have to output the number that will have index bi in the 
      	   array after all queries are performed.

   Input Size : N,Q<=100000, m<=100
   Example:
	INPUT
	 6 3 5
	 1 2 3 4 5 6
	 2 1 3
	 2 3 6
	 1 1 6
	 2 2 1 5 3
	OUTPUT
	 3 3 1 5 2  




65.Anna and Brian order n  items at a restaurant, but Anna declines to eat any of the kth item due to 
   an allergy. When the check comes, they decide to split the cost of all the items they shared; 
   however, Brian may have forgotten that they didn't split the kth item and accidentally charged 
   Anna for it. You are given n,k the cost of each of the n items, and the total amount of money that
   Brian charged Anna for her portion of the bill. If the bill is fairly split, print 'Bon Appetit'; 
   otherwise, print the amount of money that Brian must refund to Anna.

   Input Format
	The first line contains two space-separated integers denoting the respective values of n 
        (the number of items ordered) and k (the 0-based index of the item that Anna did not eat). 
        The second line contains n space-separated integers where each integer i denotes the cost 
        c[i], of item i. The third line contains an integer ,b(charged), denoting the amount of money
        that Brian charged Anna for her share of the bill.
   Output Format
	If Brian did not overcharge Anna, print Bon Appetit on a new line; otherwise, print the 
        difference (i.e.b(charged) - b(actual), ) that Brian must refund to Anna (it is guaranteed that
        this will always be an integer).

  Input Size : N<=1000000 
  Example:
	INPUT	
	 4 1
	 3 10 2 9
	 12
	OUTPUT
	 5 




66.A bus moves along the coordinate line Ox from the point x = 0 to the point x = a. After starting 
   from the point x = 0, it reaches the point x = a, immediately turns back and then moves to the
   point x = 0. After returning to the point x = 0 it immediately goes back to the point x = a and so 
   on. Thus, the bus moves from x = 0 to x = a and back. Moving from the point x = 0 to x = a or from 
   the point x = a to x = 0 is called a bus journey. In total, the bus must make k journeys. The
   petrol tank of the bus can hold b liters of gasoline. To pass a single unit of distance the bus
   needs to spend exactly one liter of gasoline. The bus starts its first journey with a full petrol 
   tank. There is a gas station in point x = f. This point is between points x = 0 and x = a. There 
   are no other gas stations on the bus route. While passing by a gas station in either direction the
   bus can stop and completely refuel its tank. Thus, after stopping to refuel the tank will contain b
   liters of gasoline. What is the minimum number of times the bus needs to refuel at the point x = f 
   to make k journeys? The first journey starts in the point x = 0. The first line contains four 
   integers a, b, f, k (0 < f < a ≤ 1000000, 1 ≤ b ≤ 1000000000, 1 ≤ k ≤ 10000) — the endpoint of the
   first bus journey, the capacity of the fuel tank of the bus, the point where the gas station is 
   located, and the required number of journeys.
   
   Example:
 	INPUT
	 6 9 2 4
	OUTPUT
	 4 




67.Your city has n junctions. There are m one-way roads between the junctions. As a mayor of the
   city, you have to ensure the security of all the junctions. To ensure the security, you have to 
   build some police checkposts. Checkposts can only be built in a junction. A checkpost at junction 
   i can protect junction j if either i = j or the police patrol car can go to j from i and then come
   back to i. Building checkposts costs some money. As some areas of the city are more expensive than
   others, building checkpost at some junctions might cost more money than other junctions. You have
   to determine the minimum possible money needed to ensure the security of all the junctions. Also 
   you have to find the number of ways to ensure the security in minimum price and in addition in 
   minimum number of checkposts. Two ways are different if any of the junctions contains a checkpost 
   in one of them and do not contain in the other. Print two integers separated by spaces. The first
   one is the minimum possible money needed to ensure the security of all the junctions. And the second
   one is the number of ways you can ensure the security modulo.

   Input Size : n<=100000 and m<=3*100000 
   Example:
	INPUT
	 3
	 1 2 3
	 3
	 1 2
	 2 3
	 3 2
	OUTPUT
	 3 1 





68.Maxwell wants to buy an apartment in a new house at Line Avenue of Metropolis. The house has n a
   partments that are numbered from 1 to n and are arranged in a row. Two apartments are adjacent if 
   their indices differ by 1. Some of the apartments can already be inhabited, others are available 
   for sale. Maxwell often visits his neighbors, so apartment is good for him if it is available for
   sale and there is at least one already inhabited apartment adjacent to it. Maxwell knows that there
   are exactly k already inhabited apartments, but he doesn't know their indices yet. Find out what
   could be the minimum possible and the maximum possible number of apartments that are good for 
   Maxwell.
   
   Input Size : N<=K<=1000000000
   Example:
	INPUT
	 6 3
	OUTPUT
	 1 3  




69.There are n people and k keys on a straight line. Every person wants to get to the office which is
   located on the line as well. To do that, he needs to reach some point with a key, take the key and
   then go to the office. Once a key is taken by somebody, it couldn't be taken by anybody else. You 
   are to determine the minimum time needed for all n people to get to the office with keys. Assume 
   that people move a unit distance per 1 second. If two people reach a key at the same time, only one
   of them can take the key. A person can pass through a point with a key without taking it. The first
   line contains three integers n, k and p (1 ≤ n ≤ 1 000, n ≤ k ≤ 2 000, 1 ≤ p ≤ 1000000000) — the 
   number of people, the number of keys and the office location. The second line contains n distinct 
   integers a1, a2, ..., an (1 ≤ ai ≤ 1000000000) — positions in which people are located initially. 
   The positions are given in arbitrary order. The third line contains k distinct integers b1, b2, ...,
   bk (1 ≤ bj ≤ 1000000000) — positions of the keys. The positions are given in arbitrary order. 
   Note that there can't be more than one person or more than one key in the same point. A person and 
   a key can be located in the same point.

   Example:
	INPUT
	 2 4 50
	 20 100
	 60 10 40 80
	OUTPUT
	 50 